Marty Mann Papers
Marty Mann Papers
- Recordings
  - Commonwealth Club Address, Mrs. Marty Mann, San Francisco, California, 03/19/1965; mann_m_056; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [body] Noted author, lecturer, and consultant - her book "A New Primer on Alcoholism" is now a classic in the field. Invited by South African government to give her recommendations on alcoholism and public health. Trained at Yale School of Alcoholic Studies. Mrs. Mann's second address to the Club!"
  - Dick Caron, Mrs. Marty Mann, Houston, Texas, 06/11/1955; mann_m_069; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
  - Dick Caron, Mrs. Marty Mann, Robesonia, PA, 06/12/1955; mann_m_070; talk to Group 6 inmates of Wynne Farm of the Texas Prison System; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
  - The Disease Concept of Alcoholism, San Francisco, California, 1974; mann_m_084; speech by Marty Mann; cassette (Box 15)
  - Dr. Dresner, Central Islip Hospital, Brooklyn, New York, mann_m_030; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
    Speech given by Dr. Dresner of Central Islip Hostipal
  - Dr. Maurice Kamp Interview: by Bill Hayes, Charlotte, North Carolina, 06/18/1961; mann_m_047; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box] Interview: Dr. Maurice Kamp by Bill Hayes / Charlotte, N.C., Council on Alcoholism / WWOK / June 18, 1961 / Speed 7.5
    [From note inside box] Dr. Maurice Kamp is a specialist in determining alcoholic content of blood by that of air samples taken from lungs. The "Breathalizer" is explained by him. / He further states that alcoholism is indeed a public health problem, particularly drunk driving and he says further that alcoholism is a disease and not a moral problem.
  - Dr. Thomas R. Jones, "Alcohol and You," Durham, North Carolina, mann_m_057; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    "Dr. Thomas T. Jones, narrator. Alcoholism as a family problem and a family disease. Help available through A.A. meetings and family doctors - can gain understanding of the disease. Literature to be found in alcoholism centers. Evaluation: Good."
  - Faith & Law in a Multicultural World, Emory, Georgia, 02/06/2002; mann_m_089; cassette (Box 15)
  - Frederick March on Alcoholism Information Week in New York, New York, NY, 1960s; mann_m_094; 12" phonodisc
    [From note inside sleeve]
    Transcript of Frederick March / Recording for Alcoholism Information Week
    Cuts 1 and 2: Family Problem (identical) / Cuts 3 and 4: National Problem (Identical) / Cuts 5 and 6: Personal Problem (identical)
    Speed: 33 1/3 rpm
    Announcement: 30 seconds each
    Family Problem: "I'm Frederick March. This is Alcoholism Information Week in New York. Alcoholism is a family disease, a disease which not only affects, the individual, but his entire family as well. Lean how you can prevent its tragedy and learn what to do. Write to: Alcoholism, New York 29, New York, which is a service of the national Council on Alcoholism, America's only voluntary national health agency for the prevention and control of this disease."
    National Problem: "This is Frederic March reminding you that this is Alcoholism Information Week in New York. alcoholism is damaging to the victim's family, his employer and his community. Learn how you can help combat the nation's fourth largest health problem. Write to: Alcoholism, etc."
    Personal Problem: "This is Frederic March reminding you that this is Alcoholism Information Week in New York. Many of us do not realize that the alcoholic is a sick man who can be helped. Someone close to you may need this help. Learn the facts of alcoholism and what you can do about it. Write to: Alcoholism, etc."
  - Industrial Symposium, October, 1959; mann_m_001; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
  - Interview of Mrs. Marty Mann, "The Good LIfe" radio program, New York, NY, 1961; mann_m_048; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front]
    Interview: Mrs. Marty Mann / For "The Good LIfe" radio program / By Jean ANderson for National Council of the Protestant Episcopal Church
    [from note on interior]
    Mrs. Marty Mann
    Organization and purpose of NCA. / Social vs. alcoholic drinking. / Number of women and men drinkers. / How families inform themselves. / How AA helps establish new patterns"
  - The Joe Driver Case, Durham, North Carolina, March, 1966; mann_m_003 (Oversize 9)
  - Martha Deane Show WOR-FM, New York, NY, 08/08/1963; mann_m_055; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box] Martha Deane Show WOR-FM / 8/8/63 / Guest - Mrs. Marty Mann, Exec. Dir. / National Council on Alcoholism
    [from inside of box] question and answer session. / Mrs. Mann particularly good, warm and expert. 40 min"
  - Mrs. Marty Mann, "Alcoholism, Past, Present, Future," Albuquerque, New Mexico
    - [1 of 2], October 1962; mann_m_026; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      [From box]
      Mrs. Marty Mann (1 of 2) / "Alcoholism, Past, Present, Future" / Talk given in Albuqyerque, N. M. / October, 1962 / Speed 3.75 / PART 1
      [From inside of box]
      Mrs. Marty Mann / Part 1
      Past attitude was that alcoholism was a moral problem. Left the churches and jails. Yet ancients know of this problem as a disease. As many diseases came out of the darkness of the middle ages they lost stigma. / Alcoholism still has it. Pioneer days into the 19th century this country was a real whisky drinking one. Temperance societies of the 19th cent. campaigned to reduce this drinking. They failed and turned to abolition days, 1850-1870. / Intense campaign against evilness of alcohol came to include the alcoholic as well. Universal picture was the drunken, skid-row bum. / 1935 Yale School of Alcohol Studies formed. AA founded and living recoveries are known and seen."
    - [2 of 2], October 1962; mann_m_027; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      [from box] / # Mrs. Marty Mann / Albuquerque, New Mexico
      "Alcoholism, Past, Present, and Future"
      October 1962 / 3.75 ips / Part 2 "
    - [1 of 2], mann_m_028; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Recording of speech given by Mrs. Marty Mann / [Note on Box] / "Alcoholism, Past, Present, Future" / Talk given in Albuquerque, N.M. / October 1962"
    - [2 of 2], mann_m_029; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Recording of Speech given by Mrs. Marty Mann in Albuquerque, NM / [Note on Box] / "Alcoholism, Past, Present, Future" / Talk given in Albuquerque, N.M. / October, 1962"
  - Mrs. Marty Mann at the Economic Club, 11/25/1946; mann_m_097; 10" phonodisc
  - Mrs. Marty Mann - Economic Club, WWJ Radio, Detroit, Michigan, 11/25/1946; mann_m_178; 16" phonodisc
  - Mrs. Marty Mann, "Help and Hope for the Alcoholic," Institute on Alcoholism, Austin,Texas, 07/19/1961; mann_m_038; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    Side 1 / "Hope + Help for the Alcoholic" / Marty Mann, at the Annual Institute on Alcoholism Studies, at, Austin Tex. 7-19-61 / Introduction 000 - 045 - - - M.M. 045 - 680, End of Tape
    Side 2 / John Park Lee, Philadelphia Penn. / AT Austin, Tex.
    000-385 Alanon + Alteen program 385 - End of Tape
    [From note inside box]
    Side 1 / Mrs. Marty Mann
    Growing knowledge and interest in disease of alcoholims [sic] shown in increased enrollments (300) at institutes like this. Now in 9th year to become a regional affair supported by 6 states. / Dr. Carr f Mayo Clinic states death rates could be reduced 50% if we used the knowledge we now have. This means bridging gap between knowledge we have and people who need to know it. / Specially difficult in field of alcoholism because of past attitude. - - - It was up to church to reform or if it failed, the law to punish. Individuals were "weaklings" and hopeless. Today surface understanding is changing. Alcoholism accepted as an illness intellectually but not yet with emotions, with deep concern. / It is whole objective of NCA to involve people, people who believe, who pass on their concern to others. Our (NCA) concern is with people in trouble, who can get well when they know what we know. / Hope and help for the alcoholic resides in people, now it resides in you. Don't forget the enormous power you have if you will take your conviction home and give it away!
    Side II
    John Park Lee
    Definition and some complexities of alcoholism outlines. Extent of problems, 5,200,000 individuals involved in a disease that, if continues, has only two prognosis, death or permanent irreversible mental impairment. Every alcoholic affects five to ten others in family, business, health agencies, the law, in schools and their friends. Whole communities are affected, some 35-40 million Americans are immediately, distressingly concerned. Disease of the whole man, body, mind and spirit. Segmented approach in past helped some possibly 2%. But today only effective answer lies in pooled resources, in our concern. NCCCA resolution outlines - work for various disciplines mentioned. Vital work of information centers listed and the role of official government and state programs endorsed. And (tax) cost will result in vast savings because of hugeness of waste caused by alcoholism.
    Al-Anon and AL-teen family group meeting demonstration is on the end of this side of tape.
    [On loose note inside box, possibly by original audio engineer]
    C.L. McTee / 210 East Davis St. / Mckinney, Texas
    There was an alanon and alteen program on the same side of an 1800' tape that I recorded John P. Lee's talk on so I let it go on tape after John's talk. you can erase it if you like"
  - Mrs. Marty Mann Memorial Service, 9/14/1980; mann_m_085; mann_m_086; mann_m_087; mann_m_088; 4 copies; cassette (Box 15)
  - Mrs. Marty Mann - NBC Catholic Hour, 03/20/1960; mann_m_045; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box]
    Mrs. Marty Mann and a / STAFF MEMBER OF GENERAL SERVICE BOARD OF ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS / Catholic Hour - -NBC / March 20, 1960 / Speed 7.5
    Mrs. Marty Mann NBC Catholic Hour
    Definition of alcoholism, a public health problem not a moral problem. Fourth most seious health problem in country. Who alcoholics are and how misguided efforts hinder and hide rather than inform and help. Symptoms explained. Final loss of control is not willful misbehavious, this is what makes alcoholism a disease. A disease o the whole man. NCA defined and explained; education and action, a clearing house for information to remove stigma. Aids in organizing local councils with information centers to advise and guide individual alcoholics and their families.
    Staff member of General Service Board of Alcoholics Anonymous
    What and why AA is. Willingness the only requirement. In AA individuals learn to live responsibly again. Human contact, one with another, is the only magic AA has. What AA is not. It is a program that grew from experience. / How to contact AA; it is almost everywhere here and in 88 other countries. AA is the place where surrender brings victory. / Al-Anon family groups explained. / "I sought God, my god eluded me, / sought my soul, my soul I could not see, / I sought my brother and I found all three." "
  - Mrs. Marty Mann's Roundtable Panel, A.P.A. 120th Annual Meeting, Los Angeles, California, 05/05/1964; mann_m_039; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From back of box] JUL 15 1964 [supposed date of duplication] / Mrs. Marty Mann's Roundtable Panel - Tuesday - Alcoholism / May 5, 1964 / A.P.A. 120th Annual Meeting, / Los Angeles, California / May 4-7, 1964"
  - Mrs. Marty Mann on "We the People," New York, NY, 05/05/1946; mann_m_090; 12" phonodisc
  - Mike Gorman [reel 1], New York, NY, mann_m_079; 1/4" reel tape (Box 15)
  - Mike Gorman [reel 2], New York, NY, mann_m_080; 1/4" reel tape (Box 15)
  - Mobilizing Your Community and Jim Hiers report on early orgAnization of affiliatecouncil, Columbia, South Carolina; Huntsville, Alabama, 06/27/1959; 07/11/1959; mann_m_031; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
    "Recording of speeches give by Mr. Yvelin Gardner and Jim Hiers"
    [Note on Box] Mr. Yvelin Gardner / "Mobilizing Your Community" / talk to new local Council on Alcoholism / Columbia, South Carolina / June 27, 1959 / Side 1
    Jim Hiers / Report on early organization of affiliate Council / Huntsville, Alabama / July 11, 1959 / Side 2"
  - National Committee on Alcoholism Annual Meeting, New York, NY, 1953
    - Disc 1, Marvin Block, M.D. Medical, 03/06/1953; mann_m_098; 10" phonodisc
    - Disc 2, Speeches by Marvin Block and Robert Fleming, 03/06/1953; mann_m_099; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 3, Talks by Robert Fleming, M.D. and Arnold Z. Pfeffer, mann_m_100; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 4, Talks by Arnold Z. Pfeffer, M.D. and AA Speech, J.P.L., mann_m_101; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 5, AA speech, J.P.L., 03/06/1953; mann_m_102; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 6, AA speech, J.P.L.; talk by Dr. Norman Vincent Peale, 03/06/1953; mann_m_103; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 7, Talk by Dr. Norman Vincent Peale, 03/06/1953; mann_m_104; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 8, Talk by Dr. Norman Vincent Peale, 03/06/1953; mann_m_105; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 9, Talk at the National Committee on Alcoholism Annual Meetings, 03/06/1953; mann_m_106; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 10, Talk by Mr. William B. Smithers - Board of Local Committee, 03/06/1953; mann_m_107; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 11, Talk by Dr. Norman Vincent Peale, 03/06/1953; mann_m_108; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 12, Talk by Mr. Edward L. Parker on Social Work and Alcoholic, 03/06/1953; mann_m_109; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 13, Talks by Rev. John Van Dyk and Mrs. Marty Mann, 03/06/1953; mann_m_110; 12" reel tape
    - Disc 14, Talk by Marty Mann, 03/06/1953; mann_m_111; 12" phonodisc
  - National Council on Alcoholism Annual Meeting and Institutes. "The Community Speaks", March 1958
    - Disc 1, address by Rev. Roger Alling, 03/28/1958; mann_m_121; 12" phonodisc
      [From index] "Why We Need a Community Program" / A Clergyman - Rev. Roger Alling, S.T.D., Corning, N.Y. Rector, Christ's Church, Episcopal; Board Member, Corning Area Committee on Alcoholism"
    - Disc 2, address by Mrs. Vera Bruyn, 03/28/1958; mann_m_122; 12" phonodisc
      [From index] "Why We Need a Community Program" / An Executive of Another Agency - Mrs. Vera Bruhn, Birmingham Ala.; Executive Director, Social Hygiene and Mental Health Association; Board Member, Birmingham Committee on Alcoholism. "
    - Disc 3, Mrs. Vera Bruyn, Irving Gottsegen, James S. Lunn, 03/28/1958; mann_m_123; 12" phonodisc
      [From index] "Why We Need a Community Program"
      An Executive of Another Agency - Mrs. Vera Bruyn, Birmingham Ala.; Executive Director, Social Hygiene and Mental Health Association; Board Member, Birmingham Committee on Alcoholism.
      A Hospital Administrator - Irving Gottsegen, Mt. Kisco, N.Y.; Assistant Director, Montefiore Hospital, New York City; Chairman, Committee on Alcoholism, Mental Health Association of Westchester County.
      A Businessman - James S. Lunn, Huntington N.Y.; President, Lunn Laminates, Inc,; Director, Empire State Chamber of Commerce; Board Member, Nassau County Committee on Alcoholism. "
    - Disc 4, James S. Lunn; James S. Lunn, Mrs. Brown, 02/28/1958; mann_m_124; 12" phonodisc
      [From index]
      A Businessman - James S. Lunn, Huntington N.Y.; President, Lunn Laminates, Inc,; Director, Empire State Chamber of Commerce; Board Member, Nassau County Committee on Alcoholism.
      A Civic Leader - Mrs. Edwin Rice Brown, Houston, Tex.; Past President, Houston Committee on Alcoholism "
    - Disc 5, Mrs. Brown, J.S.H.; J.S.H., 03/28/1958; mann_m_125; 12" phonodisc
      "Why We Need A Community Program"
      A Civic Leader - Mrs. Edwin Rice Brown, Houston, Tex.; Past President, Houston Committee on Alcoholism
      A Member off Alcoholics Anonymous - "J.S.H.," Philadelphia, PA,; Board Member, Philadelphia Committee on Alcoholism. "
    - Disc 6, J.S.H., Vernelle Fox; Vernelle Fox, 03/28/1958; mann_m_126; 12" phonodisc
      A Member off Alcoholics Anonymous - "J.S.H.," Philadelphia, PA,; Board Member, Philadelphia Committee on Alcoholism.
      "New Treatment Techniques"
      "Religious Therapy in an Alcoholic Clinic" - Vernelle Fox, M.D., Atlanta, Ga.; Medical Director, Georgian Clinic; Board Member, Metropolitan Atlanta Committee on Alcoholism"
    - Disc 7, Vernelle Fox, Anthony Zappala; Anthony Zappala, 03/28/1958; mann_m_127; 12" phonodisc
      "Religious Therapy in an Alcoholic Clinic" - Vernelle Fox, M.D., Atlanta, Ga.; Medical Director, Georgian Clinic; Board Member, Metropolitan Atlanta Committee on Alcoholism
      "Group and Activity therapies in a Clinic Setting" - Anthony Zapalla, M.D., Washington, D.C.; Chief, District of Columbia Alcoholic Rehabilitation Division; Board Member, Washington Committee on Alcoholism. "
    - Disc 8, New Treatment Techniques; The Problem of Alcoholism in Industry, 03/28/1958; mann_m_128; 12" phonodisc
      "From index]
      "Group and Activity therapies in a Clinic Setting" - Anthony Zapalla, M.D., Washington, D.C.; Chief, District of Columbia Alcoholic Rehabilitation Division; Board Member, Washington Committee on Alcoholism.
      Annual Lucheon / Presiding - Harold W. Lovell, ND, President, the National Council on Alcoholism
      Report of the President / Report of the Treasurer - R. Brinkley Smithers
      Address / "The Problem of Alcoholism in Industry" / James F. Oates, Jr., New York, NY; Chairman of the Board and President, the Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States"
    - Disc 9, The Problem of Alcoholism in Industry, 03/28/1958; mann_m_129; 12" phonodisc
      [Note from index] Annual Lucheon / Presiding - Harold W. Lovell, ND, President, the National Council on Alcoholism
  - National Council on Alcoholism 14th Annual Meeting, New York, NY, October 1958
    - Dr. Harold Rusk, 10/02/1958; mann_m_007; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      Recording of the National Council on Alcoholism's Annual Meeting. Post- Luncheon speech by Dr. Harold Rusk
      [From Interior Pamphlet]: "Annual statement about world wide nature of alcoholism as [a] disease problem. Need for demonstration center for treatment and research. Need for international cooperation in all fields of medicine, particularly in rehabilitation. Meeting Chairman, Mr. Oates, explains operation of NCA and appeals for support."
    - Dinner session, mann_m_008; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Tape recording of remarks at the 14th Annual Meeting of the National Council on Alcoholism in Utah, Dinner Session. / Side I Reports of President and Treasurer / Side II Mrs. Mann / Date: 1959 / Speed: 3.75"
  - National Council on Alcoholism Christmas Party, 12/23/1958; mann_m_083; reel tape (Box 15)
  - National Council on Alcoholism Annual Meeting, "Counterattack Against Alcoholism," Salt Lake City, Utah, 1959
    - Disc 1, Talk by Rev. Thomas J. Shipp, 03/20/1959; mann_m_112; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 2, Talks by Rev. Thomas J. Shipp and Ruth Fox, M.D., 03/20/1959; mann_m_113; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 3, Talks by Ruth Fox, M.D. and Jennings G. Olson, PH D., 03/20/1959; mann_m_114; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 4, Talk by Jennings G. Olson, 03/20/1959; mann_m_115; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 5, Talks by John R. Philip, M.D. and Joan K. Jackson, PhD., 03/20/1959; mann_m_116; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 6, Talks by Joan K. Jackson and R. Brinkley Smithers, 03/20/1959; mann_m_117; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 7, Talks by Mr. Sherman Pratt; Mrs. Marty Mann, 03/20/1959; mann_m_118; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 8, Talk by Mrs. Marty Mann, 03/20/1959; mann_m_119; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 9, Talk by Marty Mann, 03/20/1959; mann_m_120; 12" phonodisc
  - National Council on Alcoholism Annual Meeting & Institutes: "Modern Approaches to the Problem Drinker in Industry", 1960
    - Disc 1, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic, mann_m_130; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic / Alan E. Schwartz, D.E. Mackelman, David J. Myerson, MD"
    - Disc 2, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic, 03/22/1960; mann_m_131; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic / Alan E. Schwartz, D.E. Mackelman, David J. Myerson, MD
    - Disc 3, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic, 03/22/1960; mann_m_132; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 4, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic, 03/22/1960; mann_m_133; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 5, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic, 03/22/1960; mann_m_134; 12" phonodisc
    - Disc 6, Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic; The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today, 03/22/1960; 03/25/1960; mann_m_135; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic / Alan E. Schwartz, D.E. Mackelman, David J. Myerson, MD / Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today" - Harrison M. Trice, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University"
    - Disc 7, The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today, 03/25/1960; mann_m_136; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Meeting on the Homeless and Institutional Alcoholic / Alan E. Schwartz, D.E. Mackelman, David J. Myerson, MD / Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today" - Harrison M. Trice, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University
    - Disc 8, The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today; The Approach Through the Inplant Program, 03/25/1960; mann_m_137; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Problem Drinker as We See Him Today" - Harrison M. Trice, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University / "The Approach Through the Inplant Program" - Henry C. Mielcarek, Manager, Personnel Service Department, Allis-Chalmers Corporation
    - Disc 9, The Approach Through the Inplant Program; The Approach Through Alcoholics Anonymous, 03/25/1960; mann_m_138; 12" reel tape
      [Note in Album] Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Approach Through the Inplant Program" - Henry C. Mielcarek, Manager, Personnel Service Department, Allis-Chalmers Corporation / "The Approach Through Alcoholics Anonymous" - C. D'Alonzo, MD, Assistant Medical Director, E.I. du Point de Nemours & Company, Wilmington, Delaware
    - Disc 10, The Approach Through Alcoholics Anonymous; The Approach Through the Industrial Clinic, 03/25/1960; mann_m_139; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Approach Through Alcoholics Anonymous" - C. D'Alonzo, MD, Assistant Medical Director, E.I. du Point de Nemours & Company, Wilmington, Delaware / "The Approach Through the Industrical Clinic" - Frances I. Colonna, MD, Acting Director, New York University- Bellevue Medical Center Alcoholism Clinic
    - Disc 11, The Approach Through the Industrial Clinic, 03/25/1960; mann_m_140; 12" phonodisc
      [Note in Album] Morning Session / Chairman - Melville P. Dickenson, Senior Vice President, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States / "The Appraoch Through the Industrical Clinic" - Frances I. Colonna, MD, Acting Director, New York University- Bellevue Medical Center Alcoholism Clinic / Annual Luncheon / Presiding - Mr. R. Brinkley Smithers, President National Council on Alcoholism / President's Report / Treasurer's Report - Mr. Sherman Pratt, New York City
    - Disc 12 [Luncheon address], 03/25/1960; mann_m_141; 12" phonodisc